De Jesus Luvumbu Simao

07424187295 | Isimao.dejesus@gmail.com | Birmingham

Personal website: https://thesimaohub.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/lewisboss88

PERSONAL PROFILE

Energetic and fast learner, newly graduated in Bsc Computing. With almost a decade of customer service experience I acquired several transferable skills and qualities that can be applied to software development; for instance: adaptability, problem-solving skills, attention to details, customer service and especially communication skills. I am looking for an organisation where I can grow as a professional and bring fundamental value, further progressing in a full-stack ability and knowledge position.

KEY SKILLS

- Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and WordPress.
- Experience with cross-browser and cross-platform testing.
- Familiarity with web development standards and best practices
- Strong problem-solving and troubleshooting skills
- Basic knowledge of Linux/Ubuntu/Kali-Linux, C, C++, Visual basic and Java
- Practical in hardware and software of the PC (replacement cards and devices, installations, OS, BIOS setup, formatting and restoring the system.
- Solder/desolder of PCB's components (SMD and PTH, programming and managing of experimental hardware as Arduino.
- Excellent knowledge of the OS Windows and the applications of MS office Word, Excel, Power point and Publisher.
- I am fluent in 4 languages Italian, English, Portuguese and Spanish
- Full EU driving license

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Web developer freelance

Jan 2023-Present

- Responsible for understanding the client's requirements and objectives, collaborating closely with
 the client to gather information about the website's purpose, target audience, desired features, and
 design preferences.
- Creates website's structure, layout design, implements interactive elements, and ensures compatibility across various devices and browsers.

Loungers Limited- FOH Supervisor

Aug 2019-Aug 2022

- Oversee the day-to-day FOH operations, safety and customer service by the different staff members, ensuring that all the guidelines and standards on products and service of the company are followed.
- Ensured safety and customer service by training and guiding FOH staff members.
- Conducting trials and training of new staff members.
- Organizing private events, including masterclasses and private functions.

- Created positive and friendly atmosphere, engaging with patrons to boost repeat business.
- Checked identification to verify legal age requirements for all customers.
- Mixed beverages using extensive range of liquor, bitters, soda, water, sugar and fruits.
- Maintained strong hygiene by regularly sanitising bar area, touch points, tables and chairs.
- Handled anti-social and aggressive behaviour with firm and fair approach.

Opheem - Head Bartender

Sep 2019-Jan 2019

- Developed new cocktail recipes reflecting seasonal trends and unique range of craft gins.
- Undertook daily preparation of bar area and managed stock control.
- Exercised opening and closing procedures to prepare and close bar areas.
- Checked customer IDs to verify age and maintain compliance with regulations.
- Trained new bar staff members.
- Engaged enthusiastically with customers to keep atmosphere friendly and fun.
- Handled anti-social and aggressive behaviour with firm and fair approach.
- Maintained strong hygiene by regularly sanitising bar area, touch points, tables and chairs.

Freelance-Bartender/Mixologist

Oct 2016- Present

- Approached customer service with positive attitude and helpful demeanour.
- Carried out close examination of production problems to find fast solutions.
- Bartender for various private events, from wedding, staff parties, Hen parties, and charity events

EDUCATION

Arden University- Degree BSc Computing Degree

Nov 2019- 2023

Core subjects- Software Engineering, information systems in organization, computer technology, Dynamic website development, programming, quality systems in I.T systems analysis and design, management in I.T and e-Commerce systems.

The Manchester College- Business and ICT -access course

Sept 2013- 2014

Core subjects- Maths, ICT, Business and English

Alessandro Volta High School (Italy) - Diploma

Sept 2007-2009

Electronics and telecommunication

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

- Robotics and electronics.
- Photography.
- Research new computing technologies.
- Music and dance.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST